hey guys this looks like a fun one the
small circles each have an area of one
and I want to know what's the area of
the larger Circle if you want to try it
on your own pause it right now cuz I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 first from
this tangent line let's draw this radius
and call it little r and we're given
that the area of this circle is 1 so
that means PI Little R 2 will be equal
to 1 this looks important let's put a
box around it now for the larger Circle
let's get rid of the question mark and
let's draw the radius here that touches
the tangent line and let's call it Big R
since we're trying to find out what is
the area of this larger Circle we
ultimately want to know what is pi Big R
2 and this is also important let's put a
box around it and to save room let's put
these side by side next let's connect
all the centers of the circles it's
going to be composed of a big radius a
little radius another little radius and
a third little radius and if we darken
this line right here we now have two
similar right triangles and the reason
we know the right triangles is because
radi are always at right Ang to the
tangent lines let's copy this down here
and let's focus on the triangles this
piece right here is going to be little r
plus little r which is two little r and
this piece right here is going to be Big
R plus little r and now we're ready to
set up a proportion let's do this little
triangle first we're going to do one
little r over 2 little r and then we can
focus on this larger triangle this piece
is Big R and this bottom piece is going
to be 2 little r plus Big R plus little
r which is the same thing as Big R + 3
little r so the other half of the
proportion is going to be be Big R over
Big R + 3 little r on this side the
little r and the little r are going to
cancel each other out so that leaves us
1/ 12 is equal to Big R over the
quantity Big R + 3 little r next we can
cross multiply 2 * Big R is 2 Big R and
then 1 * this is just going to be this
next we can subtract Big R from both
sides of the equation on the left hand
side 2 Big R minus 1 Big R is 1 Big R
and on the right hand side these cancel
each other out to give us three little r
so we end up with Big R is equal to 3
little r let's copy down here and let's
Square both sides on the left hand side
Big R S stays as Big R S but on the
right hand side this Square will
distribute to both of these terms giving
us 3^ 2 * little R 2 and 3^2 is equal to
9 let's copy it down again and let's
multiply both sides by pi on the left
side we have Pi Big R 2 and on the right
hand side we can move this over and
we'll have 9 pi little R 2 and we know
that PI Little R 2 is equal to 1 so in
the place of this PI Little R squ we can
plug in one and this multiply by 1 isn't
doing anything so we can get rid of it
and we have now solved for pi Big R 2 so
we can update the question mark up here
to be nine and now we have the answer to
the question I want to know what's the
area of the large Circle so that'll be 9
units squared let's put a box around it
how exciting